# Daniel Stuart, Junior Web Developer

Cell: (860)977-2982 Email: dstuart85@yaĥoo.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-

stuart-5520231a1/

Github: https://github.com/Discode-Stu

Portfolio: https://dts-bottega-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

# **Summary**

My passion for web development is fueled by the satisfaction of learning something new through solving problems. I aim to create clean, powerful functions and always try to keep it simple. As a person who loves to be challenged, I look forward to applying my diverse experiences to new projects and endeavors.

# **Relevant Skills**

- Willingness to learn, critical thinking, attitude, adaptability, and empathy.
- Javascript, ReactJS, Redux, Python 3, CSS, HTML5, Git, SQL Databases, SCSS, Flexbox, CSS Grid, Redis, UML. Design Tools: Visual Studio Code, GitHub, Heroku.

## **Projects**

- Fantastic Fries: A multi-page, responsive restaurant website that utilizes HTML5, CSS3, Flexbox, CSS Grid, Animations, media queries, custom forms, responsive images, and a range of front end development techniques.
  - https://dts-bottega-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com/
- Portfolio Project: A portfolio application integrating and using API's, built with React JS, JSX, CSS, SCSS, and Node.js. Site layout with CSS Grid and Flexbox. Includes user authentication and CRUD functionality via API's and AXIOS.

https://dts-bottega-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

# **Work Experience**

### Toadstoolz Inc

Co-owner from Nov 2019 - present

Starting a small business in the competitive market of CBD lotions has drawn upon my natural skills of being a self-starter. This experience has also shown me that to succeed in any business, a positive attitude and awareness of the unique circumstances surrounding that business is essential. Along with creating a concise label for the product with Adobe Illustrator, I focus on tangible aspects of the user experience such as texture and smell by creating multiple recipes to address pertinent customer needs while working with a team.

## • Rincon Del Sol

Bartender from May 2019 - November 2019

The small town of Nederland, Colorado experienced a rapidly changing landscape of restaurants as tourism increased in recent years. I bartended in a newly opened Mexican themed restaurant and kept up

with the fast paced changes while staying grounded and focusing on customer experience, while also helping the new restaurant function more efficiently and effectively.

#### • Kirk Ulmer Construction, LLC.

Construction Laborer from April, 2017 - April, 2019

The increased tourism in Nederland not only fueled new restaurants, but also new construction. I quickly learned how to lay stucco and operate power tools and hand tools with the guidance of Kirk Ulmer. Because of my attention to detail, willingness to work, and ability to communicate these skills to others, I was tasked with training new employees that joined our team to keep up with the construction in Kirk's growing business.

### Stage Stop

Bartender from May 2015 - April 2017

I learned to bartend in a fast-paced gourmet restaurant with the unique challenges of it also being a thriving concert hall and one of the only music venues in the area. My critical thinking skills and ability to keep a positive attitude helped me to keep otherwise rowdy or dangerous situations under control, while keeping my eye on the bigger picture and always helping to improve systems within the business.

# • Professional Poker Player

2006 - present

As a person who loves to use critical thinking and problem solving in fast-paced situations, poker became one of my favorite hobbies at a young age. After spending countless hours of studying the game and doing independent research, I became a professional poker player and was able to comfortably pay my bills while staying on top of my own schedule and mental health in order to do so. As engaging and stimulating as professional poker is, I am more interested in using these skills in ways that help others and have tangible results of applications and products that better the world.

# **Education**

# **Bottega University**

Dec 2019-Aug 2020

Manchester Community College (three semesters)

Aug 2005- Dec 2006

At MCC I studied accounting, business, entrepreneurship, astronomy, and Adobe Photoshop.

**University of Vermont** (two semesters)

Aug 2004 - May 2005

I studied chemistry, mechanical engineering, and computer science along with psychology and sociology.

#### Hobbies

• In my free time I enjoy snowboarding, bicycling, hiking, basketball, golf, traveling, motorsports such as dirt biking and ATV riding, live music, and camping.